BRIA WILLIAMS

Software Developer

☑ bria.williams128@gmail.com



briawilliams.io



Philadelphia

1 am a software developer specialized in frontend and backend web development, with experience in the full life cycle of the software development process, including requirements definition, prototyping, proof of concept, design, implementation, testing, and maintenance.

WORK EXPERIENCES

Software Development Associate

Berea College | 2019 - 2020

- Managed and provided support for an undergraduate development team using lean
- Designed implementable solutions, debugged code, and managed repository and issue
- Performed security and coding standards reviews and conducted usability tests.
- Provided technical support for product owners for 7 interactive web applications.
- Led Scrum meetings and used Agile principles to guide software development.
- Reviewed and audited pull requests for functionality, security, accessibility, and efficiency.

Admissions Representative

Berea College | 2018 - 2019

- Recruited and contacted nearly 1000 high school students throughout metro areas in Kentucky, West Virginia, and Ohio.
- Reviewed and analyzed departmental reports to create a strategic travel and recruitment
- Solely planned, coordinated, and hosted annual events such as counselor luncheons

Educational Technology Support Assistant

Berea College | 2017 - 2018

- Enhanced and upgraded existing technology for academic use.
- Provided knowledge, resources and support services for faculty and staff.
- Managed a project which optimized and upgraded over 30 classrooms to equipment that is more standardized and sustainable.

Computer Science Teaching Assistant (TA)

Berea College | 2013 - 2017

- Facilitated daily after-class assistance to ensure students understood and mastered concepts taught in various computer science classes.
- Promoted to Lead Teaching Associate in 2015, managed a group of 15 CS Teaching Associates.
- Organized weekly meetings to delegate tasks and manage teaching associates.

Berea College | Summer 2015

- Researched, programmed, and built a quadrupedal (four-legged) robot.
- Programmed and built a quadrupedal robot using an Arduino, C language, and 3D-printed material.

PROJECTS

Simple To-Do App Python/Flask

This To-Do app is a simple Flask web application that serves as a to-do list for the user. The app allows the user to add items to their list, update that item's completion, as well as delete items.

SKILLS

Technical

Python/Flask Web Framework

HTML/CSS/Javascript

SQL/MySQL

Agile and Scrum development

Object-oriented design

Professional

Effective leader and communicator

Excellent task and time management

Strong problem solver

Technical writing

Public speaking

EDUCATION

BA in Computer and **Information Sciences**

Berea College 2013 - 2017

Computer Science Study Abroad

Kalinga Institute of Industrial Technology, India

Spring 2016

LANGUAGES

English (Native)

Spanish (Basic)

INTERESTS

Horror films

Eating

Travelling

